<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elementaryos on Viet&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://vietlq.github.io/tags/elementaryos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elementaryos on Viet&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:13:03 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vietlq.github.io/tags/elementaryos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Grub Font Size Bigger</title>
      <link>https://vietlq.github.io/2019/09/22/make-grub-font-size-bigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:13:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vietlq.github.io/2019/09/22/make-grub-font-size-bigger/</guid>
      <description>By default Ubuntu/ElementaryOS configure their GRUB to use very small fonts. That really hurts my eyes. I decided to play with GRUB and increase the font size. The process is rather straight forward:
 Generate a GRUB-compatible font with specified size from a TTF (type-type font) Edit high-level GRUB configuration file Regenerate low-level GRUB configurations Restart and enjoy fruit of your labour  I chose a mono-space font with size 36pt: DejaVuSansMono.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming Elementary OS</title>
      <link>https://vietlq.github.io/2019/05/11/taming-elementary-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 11:48:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vietlq.github.io/2019/05/11/taming-elementary-os/</guid>
      <description>ElementaryOS is a beautiful distro based on Ubuntu. It aims at satisfying Linux users with aesthetics or first time Linux users.
Unlike developers of most Linux distros, ElementaryOS developers are not shy to suggest you to pay for play: Purchase your copy of ElementaryOS. The default price tag is $20, which I was happy to pay. I really love the distro&amp;rsquo;s sleek UI and an option to install free or buy more software at their AppCenter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Wifi for Ubuntu on Microsoft Surface</title>
      <link>https://vietlq.github.io/2019/05/11/fix-wifi-for-ubuntu-on-microsoft-surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 11:02:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vietlq.github.io/2019/05/11/fix-wifi-for-ubuntu-on-microsoft-surface/</guid>
      <description>Random wifi drops There are some pains using Ubuntu on laptops, especially on Microsoft Surface laptop. Wifi settings are not perfect and there are random drops of wifi after 10-15 mins. I did searching and found that one has to do at least 2 things:
 Prevent MAC address randomisation by default (that reduces security)  /etc/NetworkManager/NetworkManager.conf [device] wifi.scan-rand-mac-address=no   Stop automatic power saving for wifi  /etc/NetworkManager/conf.d/default-wifi-powersave-on.conf wifi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>